Matt Wright

49 Celandine Drive Dalston London, UK E8 3XE

> T: 07595760341 B: 02 April 1976

matt@sudden.co.nz

Summary

Graduated from University of Auckland with a degree in Information Technology and Statistics in 1997 and have been involved in designing, developing and deploying computer technology and software for 15 years.

Graduated from University of Auckland with a degree in Information Technology and Statistics in 1997 and have been involved in designing, developing and deploying computer technology and software for 16 years.

Over the last 8 years this has meant leading and managing teams running various Front Office projects in Fixed Income, Equity and Credit, more recently focussed on Equity Derivatives. All projects have involved considerable contact with Front Office traders, Quants and Middle Office, involvement in planning, governance and ultimately execution of various programs of work.

Most recently involved in setting up a 3 year change program at Deutsche Bank to drastically reduce the cost per trade and overall year on year costs of running the global Equity Derivatives business. This has involved overseeing technology strategy, analysis streams, budgeting and estimation, development governance, vendor outsourcing engagement and setting up the appropriate project governance to oversee the overall program.

Experience

CTO, STITCHED. JAN 2014 - PRESENT.

Stitched.io is the combination of a Social network and a CRM system for the recruitment market. It connects together an existing candidate base, groups people into market niches and allows a recruitment company to leverage their private network to discover opportunity and better place candidates. It is build on the concept that connecting together your companies private contacts (outside of FB/Linked In etc) provides you insight and advantage that other CRM systems do not.

We are in private beta with a small number of companies over the 2014 summer before wider launch. If you are a recruitment company and interested in a demo, please contact me directly.

Technology wise Stitched is built very heavily on Neo4J and Ruby on Rails. Neo4j enables us to build our own private social network for each recruitment company. If you want to understand this a bit more have a look at my recent presentation at the Neo4j meetup. On Private Social Networks: https://skillsmatter.com/skillscasts/5179-private-social-networks

PROGRAMME MANAGER, DEUTSCHE BANK. JULY 2012 – DEC 2013.

Global IT Management - Responsible for IT delivery teams in Hong Kong, Singapore, London and New York. Responsible for multiple technology engagements involving outsourcing vendors in India, Spain and Russia. IT delivery to global front office trading desks, stakeholder management with representatives of global operations teams and collaboration with internal teams in pricing and risk functions in IT as well as delivery of major regulatory requirements.

Technology Leadership - Early adopter and sponsor of various technology initiatives including Hadoop via Cloudera, messaging solutions using Storm and Trident, and virtualised testing using Vagrant, Chef and BDD.

Programme Management - Responsible for a core 3 year technology program in Equity Derivatives delivering into Deutsche Banks strategic "Operational Excellence" program. This involves forming and presenting the business case, multi year budgeting, technology roadmaps, programme planning, vendor mobilisation and forming new teams around governance and reporting.

DIRECTOR, RBC CAPITAL MARKETS. APRIL 2009 - JUNE 2012.

FIC Derivatives Program - (Dec 2010 - Current)

This global program seeks to upgrade RBC's Interest Rate Derivatives global capability across the board from pricing, risk management to trade workflow. This involves introduction of new internal RBC analytics, and scaling up trading volumes as well as meeting regulatory requirements and also retiring legacy trade management systems. My involvement has included:

- Initial involvement in putting overall request to fund program, outlining business benefits, project goals, deliverables and timelines.
- Representing Europe and APAC business deliverables to the business, involving front office in regular workshops, working groups and requirements analysis.
- Setting up governance, project management goals and engaging CTB teams as well as downstream functions (middle and back office)
- Direct planning and execution over pricing deliverables including introducing new analytics, engagement with quants, quoting to external markets via Tradeweb and Bloomberg. Introduction of systems including multiple technologies (C++/Java/.NET). Rollout of client and server technologies over multiple geographic locations.
- Global management of pricing teams (London/New York) and European management of tactical on desk spreadsheet based development.

European Government Bonds Program – Rates Derivatives (Nov 2009 – Dec 2010)

This program involved building out a greenfield cash trading platform based on ION infrastructure to Europe, with derivatives primarily for hedging. The project was completed on time, on budget and was widely recognized as one of the most successful IT project in recent years at RBC at a board level. I was involved in:

- Laying out governance and project management structures.
- Creating, and building a new derivatives pricing team.
- Designing, architecting and introducing a new risk platform.
- Externalizing legacy analytics and deploying to a new server based infrastructure including streaming prices and datasynapse grid based deployable libraries.
- Representing the derivatives deliverables to the European swaps desk.

RBC Graduate Program (Member of the current steering committee)

While at RBC I have also participated actively in the graduate program with HR, reshaping and expanding the former graduate program, extending it, speaking at university fairs, interviewing graduates and mentoring current members of the program.

VICE PRESIDENT, DRESDNER KLIENWORT. JUN 2006 - APR 2009.

Team Lead - Exotic Equity Derivatives (Jan 2008 - May 2009)

Imagine Externalization (C#/Excel/Java) – I ran a team of 5 developers and designed the C# based solution on a complex, high profile project in the exotic equity derivatives space which decommissioned a legacy risk platform responsible for providing risk metrics on exotic derivatives into the existing Imagine systems. During this project I:

- · Replaced existing risk system which produced greek risk measures into a global Imagine instance
- Introduced structure, governance and modern software practices including Subversion, Continuous Integration (via Team City), unit testing and deployable setup artifacts.
- Replaced a Java EJB server farm with a C# Client and Java/Coherence back end.
- Built a new excel based server pricing farm using Microsoft Virtual Server and Datasynapse. There
 are now 500 identical virtual servers running intraday, end of day P&L and risk metrics.

Team Lead - Credit Derivatives (Jul 2006 - Jan 2008)

I ran a team of 5 developers and worked on and built a variety of .NET technical products for the DKIB flow and exotic credit derivatives desks. Particular highlights during this time include:

- Team Leading I was recognized for excellent organization and understanding of agile practices and mentored various other team leaders.
- Curve Analyzer I designed and built a C# Winforms GUI that integrated with Managed C++ Libraries provided by quants which enabled the exotic and flow desks to reconcile, analyze and mark to market CDS curve spreads.
- Curve Service We built both a C# WebService and C# REST Service to expose CDS B/O Spreads, CDS Index data, index tranche composition and CDO constituents. These services were multithreaded and highly used by a large Datasynapse based pricing farm.
- Managed CDO Website Built a client facing ASP.NET website allowing real time analysis and repricing of CDOs. Used C#, ASP.NET, AJAX, IIS and DataSynapse for pricing.
- CPT (Credit Portfolio Toolkit) Maintained and enhanced a C# 2.0 GUI that used genetic algorithms and monte carlo simulation to structure and analyze CDO Deals.

CONTRACT DEVELOPER, DRESDNER KLIENWORT. JUL 2002 - SEP 2005.

.NET Specialist - DAM Team. (May 2004 - Sept 2005)

DrKW.Directory .NET Components – This .NET Assembly based API is used by all windows forms and .NET websites within DrKW to securely access a certificate based LDAP Directory. The API involved Core C# Libraries, Web Services, documentation, code samples and support.

Grid Computing – Using the DataSynapse grid computing software, our team hosted, ran and configured a 600 node server farm for the calculation of intra day trading pricing. This involved learning and using Linux, java and the DataSyapse Java/.NET programming bridge.

Senior .NET Developer - Enterprise Server Team. (July 2002 - May 2004)

DrKW has a very large deployment of windows servers, covering all parts of the globe. It was my responsibility to write software to manage and monitor these servers. ASP.NET and various C# development.

CONTRACT DEVELOPER, MARINER 7 LIMITED. JAN 2002 – JUNE 2002.

Strategic HR solutions for recruitment, succession planning, 360° assessment and performance management. Further development work in ASP, COM+, SQL 2000. Evaluation of ASP.NET

SENIOR DEVELOPER, UTILYX LIMITED. JUN 2000 – Aug 2001.

Utilyx is an online energy management solution allowing buyers and suppliers of electricity to come together in a mutually beneficial market place for online procurement and energy management. Further work in ASP, COM+, SQL 2000, VB, XML, XSL and Active Directory integration. Subject of Microsoft technology case study.

DEVELOPER, GLAZIER SYSTEMS (NZ). JUL 1998 - MAY 2000.

Independent software house specializing in internet applications. Work on Microsoft IIS, Asp, COM, MTS, DHTML, Sql Server, Javascript. Commerce Server, Photoshop. Highlights include:

- Winner of the 1999 NZ TUANZ Online media award in the Information/Reference category for work with AC Nielsen.
- Complete Analysis, Design and Development of http://www.lk.co.nz/. First online Liquor store in NZ, integrated with delivery and distribution systems for Lion Nathan.

DEVELOPER, MINISTRY OF SOFTWARE (NZ). Nov 1997 – Jun 1998.

Ministry of Software (now a department of Simpl) was a software development house specializing in Client-Server Application Development in Microsoft Technologies.

Education

BCom - Degree in Information Science and Statistics from the University of Auckland. New Zealand (1994-1997)

Interests

Climbing, Mountaineering and Skiing. Ideally all in the same day! Gardening and 6 Music are also nice though. Technology wise I still enjoy coding and currently love Ruby, Angular. JS and Neo4j